Submarines
Marist Archives and Special Collections
Submarines
2.1.3.1.3.1
Marist College
  Box 1510
- Submarines, 2.1.3.1.3.1
  - Submarines: Commander J. G. Bower, circa 1914 - 1918; 1 (Box 1510)
    - [The Kaiser and Prince Joachim visiting Zeebrugge(?) after British raid one of few photos that show withered arm], 1
    - Verso: The Kaiser and Prince Joachim visiting Zeebrugge[?] after British raid one of few photos that show withered arm, 1-verso
    - [The hole in Mole at Zeebrugge[?] [?] by C3.], 2
    - Verso: The hole in Mole at Zeebrugge[?] [?] by C3., 2-verso
    - [German sub large U135 class], 3
    - Verso: German sub large U135 class, 3-verso
    - [Blockship at Zeebrugge[?] sunk in channel by British], 4
    - Verso: Blockship at Zeebrugge[?] sunk in channel by British, 4-verso
    - [Ship sinking after torpedo attack], 5
    - Verso: Ship sinking after torpedo attack, 5-verso
    - [C3 explosion Zeebrugge male at right is conning tower of C-3, hauled back by C3 explosion], 6
    - Verso: C3 explosion Zeebrugge male at right is conning tower of C-3, hauled back by C3 explosion, 6-verso
    - [U-boat hit by air-bomb. German U-boat hit by air bomb on Flanders coast], 7
    - Verso: U-boat hit by air-bomb. German U-boat hit by air bomb on Flanders coast, 7-verso
    - Note: Photos borrowed from Comm. Bower, 8
  - Submarines: Danish steamer Nordsven, circa 1914 - 1918; 2 (Box 1510)
    - [Captions Nochmalige Sprengung Das spreng kommando begibtsich (?) in Beiboot mochmals auf der Dampfer (?)], 1
    - Verso: Captions Nochmalige Sprengung Das spreng kommando begibtsich [?] in Beiboot mochmals auf der Dampfer [?], 1-verso
    - Note: Danish streamer Nordsven, 2
  - Submarines: France, circa 1914 - 1918; 3 (Box 1510)
    - [A French submarine arriving in the Dardanelles], 1
    - Verso: A French submarine arriving in the Dardanelles, 1-verso
    - [Tenente di Vascello Roland MORILLOT, comandante del sommergibile francese "MONGE"], 2
    - Verso: Tenente di Vascello Roland MORILLOT, comandante del sommergibile francese "MONGE", 2-verso
  - Submarines: Commander Konrad Gansser of U-boat 156, circa 1914 - 1918; 4 (Box 1510)
    - [(Commander Jansser) on first trip out of Germania wharf Kiel, after being built in 1914.], 1
    - Verso: (Commander Jansser) on first trip out of Germania wharf Kiel, after being built in 1914., 1-verso
    - [The broken propellor [sic] from the English torpedo that hit U156.], 2
    - Verso: The broken propellor [sic] from the English torpedo that hit U156., 2-verso
    - [Broken propeller lying on battle flag of German U-boat], 3
    - [The same propellor [sic] photographed [?] the German U-boat battle flag], 4
    - Verso: The same propellor [sic] photographed [?] the German U-boat battle flag, 4-verso
    - [The captain of the steamer seen in the distance brings the ships papers to Commander Jansser], 5
    - Verso: The captain of the steamer seen in the distance brings the ships papers to Commander Jansser, 5-verso
    - [U33 submerging in Eckenferde Bay Germany], 6
    - Verso: U33 submerging in Eckenferde Bay Germany, 6-verso
    - [Front of U156 (Commander Jansser) taken from conning tower], 7
    - Verso: Front of U156 (Commander Jansser) taken from conning tower, 7-verso
    - [Several men standing on surface of submarine], 8
    - Verso: German text[?], 8-verso
    - [no description], 9
    - Verso, 9-verso
    - [Steamer being stopped by U156 (Jansser)], 10
    - Verso: Steamer being stopped by U156 (Jansser), 10-verso
    - [U156 (Comm. Jansser) fore gun This is one of big sub, cruisers], 11
    - Verso: U156 (Comm. Jansser) fore gun This is one of big sub, cruisers, 11-verso
    - [Man at extreme left is present King Boris of Bulgaria (then crown prince) talking to Commander Jansser of U33. (Story to follow)], 12
    - Verso: Man at extreme left is present King Boris of Bulgaria (then crown prince) talking to Commander Jansser of U33. (Story to follow), 12-verso
    - [Submarine cruiser U156 (Commander Jansser) in the Canary Islands during 4 months cruise from Germany], 13
    - Verso: Submarine cruiser U156 (Commander Jansser) in the Canary Islands during 4 months cruise from Germany, 13-verso
    - [Hoisting a torpedo on board U-33 in Black Sea (Jansser story)], 14
    - Verso: Hoisting a torpedo on board U-33 in Black Sea (Jansser story), 14-verso
    - [Pet birds on U156 (Comm. Jansser)], 15
    - Verso: Pet birds on U156 (Comm. Jansser), 15-verso
    - [Commander Konrad Jansser of U-156 is assisted at his toilet, A naval reserve officer acts as barber. ], 16
    - Verso: Commander Konrad Jansser of U-156 is assisted at his toilet, A naval reserve officer acts as barber., 16-verso
    - [The crew of U 33 (Commander Jansser) in harbor in Germany Gunner[?] on the sunny side of the conning tower.], 17
    - Verso: The crew of U 33 (Commander Jansser) in harbor in Germany Gunner[?] on the sunny side of the conning tower., 17-verso
    - Three photographs with captions, 18
    - Two photographs with captions, 19
    - Three photographs with captions, 20
    - Three photographs with captions, 21
    - Two photographs with captions, 22
    - Mounted photograph with captions, 23
    - Note: German Photos from Gausser of U-156. His story is with Valeateners [?], 24
  - Submarines: Great Britain, circa 1914 - 1918; 5 (Box 1510)
    - [Crews bring graters [?] in But sub of up to date type.], 1
    - Verso: Crews bring graters [?] in But sub of up to date type., 1-verso
    - [Interior British [?] submarine The kitchen], 2
    - Verso: Interior British [?] submarine The kitchen, 2-verso
  - Submarines: Great Britain - captured steamer Parkgate, circa 1914 - 1918; 6 (Box 1510)
    - [Part 2 Reel 1 The English armed steamer "Parkgate," 3,232 tons, of the English navy (probably an auxillary cruiser). From Malta to Gibraltar ship fought the U-Boat and after a long battle was stopped or captured by the U-35.], 1
    - Verso: Part 2 Reel 1 The English armed steamer "Parkgate," 3,232 tons, of the English navy (probably an auxillary cruiser). From Malta to Gibraltar ship fought the U-Boat and after a long battle was stopped or captured by the U-35., 1-verso
    - [Part 2 Reel 1 U-35 captures the English steamer "Parkgate" The English armed steamship...], 2
    - Verso: Part 2 Reel 1 U-35 captures the English steamer "Parkgate" The English armed steamship..., 2-verso
    - [Part 2 Reel 1 The captain of the armed English steamer "Parkgate" has just come aboard the U-35. ...], 3
    - Verso: Part 2 Reel 1 The captain of the armed English steamer "Parkgate" has just come aboard the U-35. ..., 3-verso
    - [Part 2 Reel 1 Captain of the armed English steamer "Parkgate" (at foot of ladder) has just come on board the U-35 as a prisoner...], 4
    - Verso: Part 2 Reel 1 Captain of the armed English steamer "Parkgate" (at foot of ladder) has just come on board the U-35 as a prisoner..., 4-verso
    - [Part 3 Reel 1 Ship is the armed steamer "Parkgate," of 3,232 tons, of the English navy, from Malta to Gibraltar. After long battle the ship was stopped by the U-35 and sunk.], 5
    - Verso: Part 3 Reel 1 Ship is the armed steamer "Parkgate," of 3,232 tons, of the English navy, from Malta to Gibraltar. After long battle the ship was stopped by the U-35 and sunk., 5-verso
    - [Part 2 Reel 1 A boat from the captured steamer "Parkgate" comes alongside the U-35.], 6
    - Verso: Part 2 Reel 1 A boat from the captured steamer "Parkgate" comes alongside the U-35., 6-verso
    - [Part 2 Reel 1 A boat from the captured steamer "Parkgate" comes alongside the U-35.], 7
    - Verso: Part 2 Reel 1 A boat from the captured steamer "Parkgate" comes alongside the U-35., 7-verso
    - [Part 2 Reel 1 The captain of the captured English steamer "Parkgate" is coming aboard the U-35 as a prisoner of war. The boats are from the Parkgate and held members of his crew.], 8
    - Verso: Part 2 Reel 1 The captain of the captured English steamer "Parkgate" is coming aboard the U-35 as a prisoner of war. The boats are from the Parkgate and held members of his crew., 8-verso
    - [no description], 9
    - Verso, 9
    - [Part 3 Reel 1 ], 10
    - Verso: Part 3 Reel 1, 10-verso
  - Submarines: Great Britain - Sea of Marmara, circa 1914 - 1918; 7 (Box 1510)
    - [British submarine in Sea of Marmora], 1
    - Verso: British submarine in Sea of Marmora, 1-verso
    - [E-11 Submarine (British) in Sea Marmora], 2
    - Verso: E-11 Submarine (British) in Sea Marmora, 2-verso
    - [British sub E11 coming out of Dardanelles Strait being cheered by H.M.S. Grampus.], 3
    - Verso: British sub E11 coming out of Dardanelles Strait being cheered by H.M.S. Grampus., 3-verso
    - [Brit. Sub E1H in Sea of Marmora-On tower-Lt. Lawrence Lt. Boyle V.C. - in Command Lt. Stanley], 4
    - Verso: Brit. Sub E1H in Sea of Marmora-On tower-Lt. Lawrence Lt. Boyle V.C. - in Command Lt. Stanley, 4-verso
  - Submarines: Great Britain - sinking of the Korfu, circa 1914 - 1918; 8 (Box 1510)
    - [Part 1 Reel 3 The English steamer Korfu, 3695 tons with 5400 tons of iron for Genoa is sunk after crew leaves ship.], 1
    - Verso: Part 1 Reel 3 The English steamer Korfu, 3695 tons with 5400 tons of iron for Genoa is sunk after crew leaves ship., 1-verso
    - [Part 1 Reel 3 Sinking scene which follows without new caption is not same ship.], 2
    - Verso: Part 1 Reel 3 Sinking scene which follows without new caption is not same ship., 2-verso
    - [Part 1 Reel 3 The English steamer Brisbane River 4989 tons empty-for the English admirality from Malta to Baltimore shot in the waterline after crew had left ship. Picture could not be finished as English destroyer came on the scene.], 3
    - Verso: Part 1 Reel 3 The English steamer Brisbane River 4989 tons empty-for the English admirality from Malta to Baltimore shot in the waterline after crew had left ship. Picture could not be finished as English destroyer came on the scene., 3-verso
    - [Part 1 Reel 3 The English steamer Korfu], 4
    - Verso: Part 1 Reel 3 The English steamer Korfu, 4-verso
    - [Part 1 Reel 3 Sinking of the "Korfu" Footage preceding this shows a different ship captioned the "Korfu" but which is more likely the "Brisbane River" the sinking scenes of which were not obtained because an Eng. Destroyer appeared.], 5
    - Verso: Part 1 Reel 3 Sinking of the "Korfu" Footage preceding this shows a different ship captioned the "Korfu" but which is more likely the "Brisbane River" the sinking scenes of which were not obtained because an Eng. Destroyer appeared., 5-verso
    - [Part 1 Reel 3 Sinking of the Korfu], 6
    - Verso: Part 1 Reel 3 Sinking of the Korfu, 6-verso
    - [Part 1 Reel 3 Sinking of the Korfu by the U-35], 7
    - Verso: Part 1 Reel 3 Sinking of the Korfu by the U-35, 7-verso
    - [Part 1 Reel 3 Sinking of the Korfu], 8
    - Verso: Part 1 Reel 3 Sinking of the Korfu, 8-verso
    - [Part 1 Reel 3 Sinking of the Korfu], 9
    - Verso: Part 1 Reel 3 Sinking of the Korfu, 9-verso
    - [Part 1 Reel 3 Sinking of the Korfu], 10
    - Verso: Part 1 Reel 3 Sinking of the Korfu, 10-verso
    - [Part 1 Reel 3 Sinking of the "Korfu"], 11
    - Verso: Part 1 Reel 3 Sinking of the "Korfu", 11-verso
    - [Part 1 Reel 3 Sinking of the "Korfu"], 12
    - Verso: Part 1 Reel 3 Sinking of the "Korfu", 12-verso
    - [Part 1 Reel 3 Sinking of the Korfu], 13
    - Verso: Part 1 Reel 3 Sinking of the Korfu, 13-verso
    - [Part 1 Reel 3 Sinking of the Korfu], 14
    - Verso: Part 1 Reel 3 Sinking of the Korfu, 14-verso
    - [Part 1 Reel 3 Sinking of the Korfu], 15
    - Verso: Part 1 Reel 3 Sinking of the Korfu, 15-verso
    - [Part 1 Reel 3 Sinking of the Korfu], 16
    - Verso: Part 1 Reel 3 Sinking of the Korfu, 16-verso
    - [Part 1 Reel 3 Brisbane River], 17
    - Verso: Part 1 Reel 3 Brisbane River, 17-verso
    - [Part 1 Reel 3 Sinking of the Korfu], 18
    - Verso: Part 1 Reel 3 Sinking of the Korfu, 18-verso
    - Note: U-35 prints, Sinking of the "Korfu," also "Brisbane River," film is not consistent here, 19
  - Submarines: Great Britain - sinking of the Patagonier, circa 1914 - 1918; 9 (Box 1510)
    - [Part 2 Reel 2], 1
    - Verso: Part 2 Reel 2, 1-verso
    - [Part 2 Reel 2 The sinking English steamer Patagonier, 3,832 tons, said to have been bringing sugar from Cuba.], 2
    - Verso: Part 2 Reel 2 The sinking English steamer Patagonier, 3,832 tons, said to have been bringing sugar from Cuba., 2-verso
    - [Part 2 Reel 2], 3
    - Verso: Part 2 Reel 2, 3-verso
    - [Part 2 Reel 2], 4
    - Verso: Part 2 Reel 2, 4-verso
    - [Part 2 Reel 2 U-35 The sinking of English steamer Patagonier], 5
    - Verso: Part 2 Reel 2 U-35 The sinking of English steamer Patagonier, 5-verso
    - Note: U-35 Sinking of Patagonier, m.g. under retouched, 6
  - Submarines: Great Britain - sinking of the Nentmore, circa 1914 - 1918; 10 (Box 1510)
    - [No. 114-M], 1
    - Verso: No. 114-M, 1-verso
    - [No 114-T Last of series of views[?] showing sinking of "Nentmore" English steamship by U-35, German submarine.], 2
    - Verso: No 114-T Last of series of views[?] showing sinking of "Nentmore" English steamship by U-35, German submarine., 2-verso
    - [No 114-R], 3
    - Verso: No 114-R, 3-verso
    - [No 114-Q], 4
    - Verso: No 114-Q, 4-verso
    - [No 114-A See pictures of sinking in 114 series. U-35 film Part 4 Reel 3 The English steamship "Nentmore" of 3,535 tons carrying 5,658 tons of wheat from S. America to Genoa is...], 5
    - Verso: No 114-A See pictures of sinking in 114 series. U-35 film Part 4 Reel 3 The English steamship "Nentmore" of 3,535 tons carrying 5,658 tons of wheat from S. America to Genoa is..., 5-verso
    - [No. 114-P], 6
    - Verso: No. 114-P, 6-verso
    - [No. 114-L], 7
    - Verso: No. 114-L, 7-verso
    - [No 114-K], 8
    - Verso: No 114-K, 8-verso
    - [No 114-T (Part 4 Reel 3)], 9
    - Verso: No 114-T (Part 4 Reel 3), 9-verso
    - [No 114-I One of series in sinking of English steamship "Nentmore" by U-35], 10
    - Verso: No 114-I One of series in sinking of English steamship "Nentmore" by U-35, 10-verso
    - [No 114-H], 11
    - Verso: No 114-H, 11-verso
    - [No 114-G], 12
    - Verso: No 114-G, 12-verso
    - [No. 114-F Part 4 Reel 3 Nentmore sinks], 13
    - Verso: No. 114-F Part 4 Reel 3 Nentmore sinks, 13-verso
    - [No. 114-D Eng. steamship "Nentmore" sunk by U-35], 14
    - Verso: No. 114-D Eng. steamship "Nentmore" sunk by U-35, 14-verso
    - [No 114-E The steamer Nentmore struck by shell from deck gun of U-35], 15
    - Verso: No 114-E The steamer Nentmore struck by shell from deck gun of U-35, 15-verso
    - [No. 114-C The English steamer "Nentmore" 3535 tons with 5658 tons of wheat en route from South America to Genoa is stopped. After taking crew prisoners the ships were bombed.], 16
    - Verso: No. 114-C The English steamer "Nentmore" 3535 tons with 5658 tons of wheat en route from South America to Genoa is stopped. After taking crew prisoners the ships were bombed., 16-verso
    - [No. 114-O], 17
    - Verso: No. 114-O, 17-verso
    - [No 114-S], 18
    - Verso: No 114-S, 18-verso
    - [No. 114-B Part 4 Reel 3 The English steamship "Nentmore" of 3535 tons laden with 5,658 tons of wheat en route from So. America to Genoa is stopped by the U-35. After taking the crew prisoners the ship was bombed. Steamship equipped with hidden or camoflouged guns. ], 19
    - Verso: No. 114-B Part 4 Reel 3 The English steamship "Nentmore" of 3535 tons laden with 5,658 tons of wheat en route from So. America to Genoa is stopped by the U-35. After taking the crew prisoners the ship was bombed. Steamship equipped with hidden or camoflouged guns., 19-verso
  - Submarines: Greece - sinking of the India, circa 1914 - 1918; 11 (Box 1510)
    - [Part 3 Reel 2 Sinking of the "India " of Greece by the U-35], 1
    - Verso: Part 3 Reel 2 Sinking of the "India " of Greece by the U-35, 1-verso
    - [Part 3 Reel 2 The Sinking "India" of Greece which has been bombed by the U-35], 2
    - Verso: Part 3 Reel 2 The Sinking "India" of Greece which has been bombed by the U-35, 2-verso
    - [Part 3 Reel 2 Sinking "India" of Greece Bombed by the U-35 The cross on the shipside of the sinking steamer is the Greek sign of loyalty.], 3
    - Verso: Part 3 Reel 2 Sinking "India" of Greece Bombed by the U-35 The cross on the shipside of the sinking steamer is the Greek sign of loyalty., 3-verso
    - [Part 3 Reel 2 The sinking "India" of Greece, Greek steamer, 2933 tons,, laden with 3,883 tons of coal, from Cardiff to Oran(?), used, is stopped by the U-35, bombed and sunk.], 4
    - Verso: Part 3 Reel 2 The sinking "India" of Greece, Greek steamer, 2933 tons,, laden with 3,883 tons of coal, from Cardiff to Oran[?], is stopped by the U-35, bombed and sunk., 4-verso
    - [Part 4 Reel 2 Sinking of "India" of Greece], 5
    - Verso: Part 4 Reel 2 Sinking of "India" of Greece, 5-verso
    - [Part 4 Reel 2 Sinking of "India" of Greece], 6
    - Verso: Part 4 Reel 2 Sinking of "India" of Greece, 6-verso
    - [Part 4 Reel 2 Sinking of "India" of Greece (last scene in sinking)], 7
    - Verso: Part 4 Reel 2 Sinking of "India" of Greece (last scene in sinking), 7-verso
    - [Part 3 Reel 2 (last scene of sinking in part 3) The Greek steamer India, 2933 tons, with 3,883 tons of coal from Cardiff to Oran(?) is stopped, bombed and sunk.], 8
    - Verso: Part 3 Reel 2 (last scene of sinking in part 3) The Greek steamer India, 2933 tons, with 3,883 tons of coal from Cardiff to Oran[?] is stopped, bombed and sunk., 8-verso
    - [Part 4 Reel 2 "India" of Greece], 9
    - Verso: Part 4 Reel 2 "India" of Greece, 9-verso
    - [Part 3 Reel 2 The sinking "India" of Greece], 10
    - Verso: Part 3 Reel 2 The sinking "India" of Greece, 10-verso
    - [Part 3 Reel 2 The "India" of Greece stopped by the U-35, boarded by her bombing crew and sunk.], 11
    - Verso: Part 3 Reel 2 The "India" of Greece stopped by the U-35, boarded by her bombing crew and sunk., 11-verso
    - Note: U-35 prints, Sinking of "India" of Greece, 12
  - Submarines: Max Horton, circa 1914 - 1918; 12 (Box 1510)
    - [M1 English sub formerly commanded by Capt. Max Horton 12 inch gun], 1
    - Verso: M1 English sub formerly commanded by Capt. Max Horton 12 inch gun, 1-verso
    - [COPYRIGHT RESERVED. This photograph must not be reproduced in any way without permission. Further copies may be ordered from the Imperial War Museum, South Kensington, S.W. 7], 2
    - Verso: COPYRIGHT RESERVED. This photograph must not be reproduced in any way without permission. Further copies may be ordered from the Imperial War Museum, South Kensington, S.W. 7, 2-verso
    - [The Hela, fast German naval vessel torpedoed by Brit. Sub. (Max Horton in E9).], 3
    - Verso: The Hela, fast German naval vessel torpedoed by Brit. Sub. (Max Horton in E9)., 3-verso
    - [Interior of submarine, one man sleeping], 4
    - Verso: Submarine control room, man sleeping when they can snatch few winks, 4-verso
    - [Old chateau outside Bruges(?), used as kind of country club by German officers.], 5
    - Verso: Old chateau outside Bruges[?], used as kind of country club by German officers., 5-verso
  - Submarines: Illustrations, undated; 13 (Box 1510)
    - [Sinking of the Formdars[?] Painted by [?] of Berlin.], 1
    - Verso: Sinking of the Formdars[?] Painted by [?] of Berlin., 1-verso
    - [The Sinking of the German Light Cruiser "Nurmberg". This picture, published in a German illustrated papers purports[?] It shows the sinking of the German light cruiser "Nurmberg" by English armored cruisers, after the battle of the Falkland Islands. The picture is supposed to represent the incident at the moment when the "Nurmberg" summoned by the English flagship upheld[?] the "German warships never surrender."], 2
    - Verso: The Sinking of the German Light Cruiser "Nurmberg". This picture, published in a German illustrated papers purports[?] It shows the sinking of the German light cruiser "Nurmberg" by English armored cruisers, after the battle of the Falkland Islands. The picture is supposed to represent the incident at the moment when the "Nurmberg" summoned by the English flagship upheld[?] the "German warships never surrender.", 2-verso
    - [p. 376 of "Der Krieg 1914-1919 in Wort and Bild" used in World's Work May 1928 "Raiders of the Deep" Sinking of the British battleship "Triumph" by Otto von Hersing May 25, 1915], 3
    - Verso: p. 376 of "Der Krieg 1914-1919 in Wort and Bild" used in World's Work May 1928 "Raiders of the Deep" Sinking of the British battleship "Triumph" by Otto von Hersing May 25, 1915, 3-verso
    - Caption: The "U-21" bags two english merchantmen, 4
    - [Painting of a ship out at sea tossed by waves, second ship in background], 5
    - Verso: Passing through the Submarine zone USS Kimberly, destroyer convoying the Leviathan, troop transport, through the war zone during the World War. From a paint by Burnell Poole. Free - War Dept made for "How we Nearly Lost the War" March 1927 WW, 5-verso
    - Caption: The Work of A German Torpedo. English steamer Maseton sinking south of Ireland, shot at night out of convoy. In his installment Mr. Thomas will tell of raids o this kind on Allied merchant vevssels. (handwritten:) Cut made for April 1928., 6
    - Caption: Cut made for May 1928., 7
    - Caption: A SHIPPING CASUALTY OF THE WORLD WAR An authentic photograph taken from a British blimp of a merchant ship sinking rapidly after being torpedoed by a German submarine on December 19, 1917. A British destroyer hrueld a depth charge after the submerged submarine, a hit being revealed by the appearance of oil on the surface thirteen minutes after the freighter had been torpedoed., 8
    - [Wooden ship being tossed by waves, second ship in foreground], 9
    - [Romanticized painting of submarine control room], 10
    - [Sinking of the U.S.S. Jacob Jones by George E. Browne], 11
    - Verso: Sinking of the U.S.S. Jacob Jones by George E. Browne, 11-verso
    - [From a painting by Wilhelm Ritschel a heavy[?] and majestic relic of the sea's more chivalrous days.], 12
    - Verso: From a painting by Wilhelm Ritschel a heavy[?] and majestic relic of the sea's more chivalrous days., 12-verso
    - [Destruction of the German destroyer S.126 by English Submarine E9], 13
    - Verso: Destruction of the German destroyer S.126 by English Submarine E9, 13-verso
    - [Painting of submarine interior, man in uniform sitting, three men standing], 14
    - [ A WORLD WAR EVEN RE-LIVES IN THE BRUSH OF AN ARTIST BURNELL POOLE, A MARINE ARTIST, HAS COMPLETED THIS NEW PAINTING FOR THE NAVY DEPARTMENT COLLECTION. IT DEPICTS THE AMERICAN DESTROYERS, KIMBERLY AND DAVIS CONVOYING THE LEVIATHAN THROUGH THE WAR ZONE, DURING THE WORLD WAR, AND IT NOW HANGS IN THE HISTORICAL COLLECTION OF THE NAVY DEPARTMENT, IN WASHINGTON, D.C.], 15
    - Verso: A WORLD WAR EVEN RE-LIVES IN THE BRUSH OF AN ARTIST BURNELL POOLE, A MARINE ARTIST, HAS COMPLETED THIS NEW PAINTING FOR THE NAVY DEPARTMENT COLLECTION. IT DEPICTS THE AMERICAN DESTROYERS, KIMBERLY AND DAVIS CONVOYING THE LEVIATHAN THROUGH THE WAR ZONE, DURING THE WORLD WAR, AND IT NOW HANGS IN THE HISTORICAL COLLECTION OF THE NAVY DEPARTMENT, IN WASHINGTON, D.C., 15-verso
    - [Photo by Edwin Lemik[?] New York], 16
    - Verso: Photo by Edwin Lemik[?] New York, 16-verso
    - [Otto von Hersing in the U-21 (also called U-51) sinks 2 British freighters. Belongs with 2nd installment "Raiders of the Deep" "Prima" is mentioned in story], 17
    - Verso: Otto von Hersing in the U-21 (also called U-51) sinks 2 British freighters. Belongs with 2nd installment "Raiders of the Deep" "Prima" is mentioned in story, 17-verso